All right, Burner Nation. Welcome to
this episode of Burner Bros. I am, of
course, your host, Josh, and I cannot
tell you how excited I have been for
this guest and this episode. I know you
have seen him probably in several
places. John Kuryaku, thank you so much
for joining us today. John, just a a
real quick uh background here. John was
a former CIA analyst, counterterrorism
officer who became really widely known
predominantly as as a government
whistleblower after he was the first to
publicly confirm the CIA's use of
waterboarding during enhanced
interrogation uh program and techniques
uh back in 2007. He has since gone on to
be an advocate for government
accountability, whistle protection, and
civil liberties. And you've probably
seen John uh in several uh of the uh the
more higher profile podcasts and shows
out there. He has been making the
circuit this last year. I mean, you've
been on Joe Rogan, Seth Ryan, Dr. Phil,
The Diary of the [clears throat] CEO.
Man, you have hit all the boxes. I'll
tell you what, John. Thanks so much for
joining us today.
>> Thank you, Josh. This is going to be a
lot of fun. I really appreciate the
invitation.
>> So, Burn Nation, you know, we always
talk about situational awareness. We
always talk about how everything that's
going on in the country and in the world
affects you on a day-to-day basis
because it really does. And
unfortunately, I think a lot of people
out there just don't really have that
grasp and understand how what goes on a
state, two states, a country half a
world away can affect them on a
day-to-day basis. And John, I I really
want to get into because you have so
much knowledge. I mean, you know, you've
got decades at the CIA and then the
advocacy after that just continuing uh
with that knowledge is is is is so great
and such, you know, can lend to to what
we're talking about here today.
>> Thank you. Thank you. I'm so glad that
you want to talk about situational
awareness because this is something
that's become so important in my life
and continues to be important. I'll tell
you, when I was in college, I was a
normal kid. I was what 18, 19, 20 years
old and I was not situationally aware. I
I went to school here in Washington at
George Washington University and I
remember specifically freshman year I
was 18 years old. It was the last warm
evening of the year. We knew it was cuz
this cold front was coming in and I
wanted to go for a walk and it was like
10:30 at night and nobody on my floor
wanted to go for a walk with me. So, I
went alone and I remember going straight
down 19th Street toward Constitution
Avenue and I got just past the the
[clears throat] uh State Department and
I hear a voice say, "Excuse me, do you
have the time?" And I turned and there
was a guy holding a uh like a tube, like
a big mailing tube, but like a baseball
bat. And he says, "Give me your watch
and your wallet." And I put up my hands
to protect myself. And in a split
second, I thought to myself, I bet that
tube is empty. And I took a swing at him
and I hit him and it stunned him and he
ran off. [snorts] That was the first
time something like that had ever
happened to me. And I was determined to
be more situationally aware. Okay, I
graduate. I go to graduate school, get
my degree there, and I get recruited out
of graduate school into the CIA. I spend
the first seven and a half years of my
career as an analyst and then I make a
very unusual for the time transition
into counterterrorism operations. So I
go through all the operational training
and what I really took to the most was
surveillance and surveillance detection.
Talk about the the the gold standard of
situational awareness. So flash forward
five more years, 9/11 takes place and I
go to Pakistan to be the CIA's chief of
counterterrorism operations right after
the 9/11 attacks. I was staying in a
small guest house. They they wanted to
put me in the Marriott. I said, "Are you
insane? What's the first place that
they're going to blow up? It's the
Marriott. Put
>> a bigger target on me, please." and and
I spent the first night there and they
moved me into a little guest house and
six weeks later they blew up the
Marriott and killed half the people
inside. So I'm in this little guest
house and every day I would leave for
work at a different time and take a
different route. So I never established
a pattern.
>> One day I noticed there's a guy on a
motorcycle with a red helmet and he's
trying really hard to stay in my blind
spot. So I'd speed up, he'd speed up. I
slow down, he slows down. I change
lanes. He's changing with me. And I was
like, "Dang it." So, I I jotted a note
to myself. I always kept a little
notebook. This is before you could take
notes on a phone. I always kept a little
notebook in my pocket and a pen. So, I
wrote down his license number. The only
reason he even came to my attention was
that he was wearing the helmet. And I
had never seen anybody in Pakistan
wearing a a motorcycle helmet. I didn't
even know you could buy them there. So,
I get to the entrance to the diplomatic
quarter and he breaks off. Normal
workday. I'm working 14, 15, 16 hours.
So, I arrive at during dark uh hours and
I leave after dark. I leave the
diplomatic quarter. He's back on me
again. So, now I know I'm in trouble. I
get home. I'm worried. I can't sleep.
I'm nervous. The next morning, I get up
at 5:00 in the morning. I open the door
crack. I look up and down the street. I
don't see anybody. I check under my car
with the mirror for bombs and tracking
devices. I don't see anything. I get
about a block, two blocks, and he's on
me again. So, I get to the embassy. I
wait for the security officer to come in
and I said, "I'm under surveillance. I'm
positive I'm under surveillance." He's
like, "Okay." I explained what the story
was. And uh he says, "We have to wait
for the chief to come in." Chief comes
in around 7. I go in. I said, "I'm under
surveillance. I'm 100% sure." And I
explained and he's like, "Well,
you know what you have to do." And I
said, "I know. I know what I have to
do." He's like, "Don't worry. We're
going to have a team out there. We're
going to have three, four cars.
Everybody's going to surround you. It's
we're going to we're going to help.
Everybody's going to be helped." I was a
nervous wreck all day. I had never
killed anybody. I never had to. And so
that afternoon at 3:00,
I had a meeting in a safe house that we
shared with the Pakistani intelligence
service. And on my way out and Josh, I
don't know what possessed me to do this,
but as I get to the door to the leave to
leave, I stopped and I turned and I
said, "General Muhammad, are you
following me?"
And he said, "No. Why?" And I said,
"Because I'm under surveillance. I'm
positive that I'm under surveillance.
and when I see the guy this afternoon,
I'm gonna kill him. And I never saw him
again because of course I was under
surveillance. The problem was they chose
the worst surveillance officer in the
entire Pakistani intelligence service.
So instead of being two blocks back
where I may not notice him, he's right
next to me like it's an episode of Kjack
or something. And if it wasn't for that
momentary questioning,
that guy would be in the ground today.
>> What what keyed you off that it was was
that Pakistani intelligence? Was that uh
Pakistani military? I guess what?
>> Yeah, it was the military
>> off that that that they could have been
involved to ask that question.
You know, ev what they told us in
training was that every once in a while
the good guys may just stop and take a
look at you just to see what you're
doing when you're not with them.
>> Okay?
>> Just to keep the honest people honest.
And and you know, it turned out that
they were sitting around a table one day
and somebody said, you know, the new guy
at the American embassy, John, really
nice guy. And [snorts] everybody agreed,
yeah, he's a really nice guy. And then
somebody said, "You know what? Nobody's
that nice. He's probably pretending to
be nice just so that we'll drop our
guard. Let's see what he's doing when
he's not here."
And they got the worst surveillance
officer in the entire service. And I was
going to genuinely I was going to kill
him that afternoon.
>> What a you know how acute of a story
when it comes to situational awareness.
you know now now mo most of our
listeners are not CIA operatives
[laughter]
>> are not uh you know the chief of
counterterrorism operations in Pakistan
but [laughter]
working with being in law enforcement
for so long being a SWAT guy for so long
doing all this stuff
>> you know I know there's a lot that I can
bring into my personal life from what I
learned what do you think you know what
are those things you've learned I mean
as the pinnacle as the epitome of
surveillance of blending in of being
safe. What are those things that the
average person that you can bring down
to because I'm I assume there's a bunch
of overlap there.
>> Oh yeah. And that's a life-saving
potentially life-saving question.
>> So after I left Pakistan, after I left
the CIA, there was a CIA contractor. So
he was on contract with the CIA, but had
never gone through any of the training.
He's essentially a civilian that has a
classified job. He did exactly what you
are not supposed to do in this kind of
situation. So he's in Lahore, Pakistan,
stuck in traffic and in his side view
mirror, he sees two guys coming up
alongside of him in a on a motorcycle.
One of them is pulling out a gun as he's
looking in the side view mirror. So he
takes out his gun and shoots both of the
motorcyclists and kills him dead. So
then what would you do? What would I do?
I'd get the hell out of there.
He puts it in park, calls the consulate,
and sits there and waits for them to
come. This gigantic mob formed rocking
the car trying to pull him out of the
car. The the consulate sends a security
team over to help him out. On the way to
help him out, they hit and kill a guy on
a bicycle.
>> So, they can't get to the site where
he's most in need of help. Finally, the
Pakistani police arrive. They arrest
him, thus saving his life, but they
charge him with two counts of murder
and it was 6 months before the US
government was able to negotiate his
release from Pakistan. So, rule number
one that they taught us in training and
this is applicable to everybody in the
audience, get out of the kill zone at
the first sign of trouble. Get out. I
have a friend who was on the 87th floor
of Tower 1 on 911 and she survived and I
was calling and calling and calling that
day and the circuits were down. You may
remember I finally got through and she
answered the phone. I said, "My god,
Julia, you made it out alive." And she
said, "Yeah, I did." I said, "How did
you do it?" And she said, "John, I was
born in Cheschna."
>> And we learned young that at the first
sign of trouble, get out.
you. We talk about so much about whether
it's in a tactical situation or whether
it's in a situation you're talking about
getting off the X and how important it
is, you know,
not to when uh I teach active shooter a
lot and we talk about how
>> how uh
>> your brain will do things to to to try
to rationalize with you and about how
many people during an active shooter
think, man, that's odd that there's
fireworks in my office building at
Tuesday on at at 10:00 a.m. That's not
that's your brain rationalizing. You
know that that's you have to take things
at at sometimes at their worst value in
order to activate that
self-preservation. And like you said,
get out at the first sign. Don't try to
rationalize. Don't try to explain it
away. Just go. And that's was what a
what an important
>> May may I add something too? when I was
in when I was in CIA um uh
counterterrorist operations training, I
took two classes, counterterrorist
operations and advanced counterterrorist
operations. And then there's
counterterrorist driving, all different
kinds of things. So, there was one
situation where we were we were at the
CIA training facility called the farm
>> and uh and I'm in a mockup of of a
really seedy Central American hotel like
zero stars,
bugs and rats and stuff like that. I've
got a cot and I've got a table and a
chair and there's a knock on the door
and I said, "Who is it?" I didn't say
come in. And I said, "Who is it?" And
two guys just walk in. One is holding up
a vacuum cleaner and they're speaking
very quickly in Spanish. And I don't
know what made me do it, but I'm trying
to make to keep direct eye contact with
the guy with the vacuum cleaner. Well,
the guy the the second guy comes from
behind him and just goes bang bang bang
and shoots me three times with a with a
paint paintball gun. I was like, "Damn
it." [snorts] And he said, "What are you
doing?" He said, "When when you said,
"Who is it?" and we just came in, "Your
job is to open fire."
>> Yeah.
>> And get off the X.
>> So he says, "Go back out to the van."
There were seven other students in the
van. Don't tell anybody what happened.
So I go to the van and everybody's
looking at me and I have these three
paintball spots right over my heart.
>> You don't got to tell them.
>> And they just, "Oh, oh." Well, one by
one by one, all eight of us got killed
in the exercise,
>> man.
>> But I I'll tell you what, it's a lesson
I will never ever forget. Ever. And I
never allowed myself to be in a
situation like that ever again. So when
you're you know through through all your
training and all those thing and then
your experience especially overseas here
in the US and wherever else you may or
may not have be able to confirm you have
been or have not been uh [laughter] so
you know when you're
>> where I had to throw the money away at
the airport so I didn't have any when I
came back.
>> That's right. Yeah. [laughter]
U you know what when you're out and you
might be going about your normal
business. You might be headed to a
meeting. It's you're not doing some
crazy black op out there. you're just
going to work. What are those things
that as as an operative an as an analyst
who understands that they are in you
know a bit more of a critical role and a
critical environment than most normal
people but what are those things that
you're looking at? You're walking to
work. You're looking you you have that
elevated situational awareness. What
does that look like
>> uh rationally and practically you know
as you're walking across the street? It
can be in as innocuous as keeping six
feet between you and the car in front of
you at red light. Simple as that.
>> So you have a way out.
>> If you need to get out, you can get out.
Even if you need to, you know, bump the
car in front of you to to push them out
of your way to get out, you can get out.
Walking. I actually have always
preferred uh foot SDRs, foot
surveillance detection routes, because
you can stop and look in a store window
and use the reflection to see who's
behind you. You can do something called
stairstepping, which is you go up a
block, make a right, go up a block, make
a left, make a right, make a left, make
a right, like a like a stair a
staircase. And in fact, every time you
stop at that corner, you look both ways
to see, you know, if there aren't any
cars coming. But really, you're looking
to see if you're being followed. And
we're not talking necessarily about
terrorism. We could be talking about,
you know, walking down the street in
Oaklair, Wisconsin. You're talking about
the possibility of being mugged, purse
snatching, you know, anything. It could
be just regular normal street crime that
happens in every city across America
every single day.
No, that that's what what a great what a
great tactic and and tip both on the you
know the driving. We always talk we see
so many of these road rage incidents,
right? And you know
>> exactly what I was first piece of advice
is drive away. You got to pop a curb if
you got to go.
>> That's right.
>> Do it.
>> You can you can fix the rim later.
>> That's it.
>> Drive away.
>> Or you may be going the wrong way on a
street for for a second, you know, and
well that's illegal. Hopefully a cop
stops you because [laughter] you know
like you have a girlfriend issue. My my
girlfriend and I have this ongoing joke
because she says I I drive like a crazy
person and um and I drive very
defensively and I the joke is I always
say, "How many times have you been shot
while I was driving?" Zero times. You've
been shot zero times while I've been
driving. So you should be thanking me.
>> That's it. That's it. [laughter]
>> Oh man, that's great. So, so as we kind
of open up our lens a little bit and
open our perspective and we you know we
talk about situation awareness on a very
uh a very acute level on a very personal
level we see a lot of things going on
obviously here in the country and and
definitely internationally especially
within the last three years the last 12
months the last six months and it's all
seeming to
>> to get a little bit closer to home you
know I I think a lot of a lot of people
don't quite understand how that affects
them at home and how that affects their
day-to-day life and their day-to-day
safety. You have a very interesting
perspective because that was your job to
understand how what's going on a
hemisphere away
>> will affect a person in Dayton, Ohio,
you know, on a day-to-day basis. what
are you seeing compared to to what you
saw back in the 90s in the early 2000s
post 911 you know what are you seeing in
the last you know year or or however
long uh that's really playing a big
impact and having a big big impact on
the day-to-day American safety
>> yeah
well as background
>> question so [laughter]
>> it's it's a very important question as
background think of it this way
the FBI the CIA TSA a NSA, everybody has
to be on top of their game 100% of the
time. The bad guys have to get lucky
once.
Once. And we can't even gauge what might
happen with a lone wolf, somebody who's
self-radicalized watching YouTube
videos, for example.
>> And so, the worst can happen literally
anywhere in America. You have to
constantly be aware of your
surroundings. Your side view mirrors,
your rearview mirror are your best
friends when you're in the car.
Constantly be scanning them. Constantly
think of a way out if you're stuck in
traffic, for example. And like you say,
if that means jumping a curb or going
the wrong way down a oneway street, do
it. Pay the $60 fine later.
But look at it in the respect that if
there is a cop there to stop you, that's
good because that that cop is going to
protect you. Okay, number one. Number
two, these big international events like
the war in Ukraine, the war in Gaza, the
war in Iran, they make people very
angry. Maybe not a lot of people are
going to be angry enough to actually do
something and take matters into their
own hands, but one or two or five might.
And that might mean shooting somebody
from the roof of a building. Or it might
mean walking into a shopping center and
opening fire or walking into a school
and opening fire. You just never know.
And so you have to be prepared for that
kind of thing. Again, I I keep repeating
myself or I keep repeating you. It's all
about situational awareness. Um, I I'm I
in the last couple of years I've become
friends with with an A-list Hollywood
name, A-list. And I happen to be
visiting him. I'm going to say like four
weeks ago.
And I know everybody in his circle. He's
got his publicist and his assistant and,
you know, this guy and that guy and the
accountant and the agent and they're all
hanging around all the time. So, I'm
saying hi to everybody. There was a guy
that I I didn't know and I said, "Hi,
I'm John." He said, "Oh, I know. We've
met." And I said, "Oh, we have." And he
said, "Yeah, Islamabad 2002 in the safe
house." And I said, "Oh, I remember
you." Now, this is 24 years ago. I said,
"I remember you." He said, "Right, you
finished your tour and went back to
headquarters." I said, 'Right, I never
saw you again. What did you do? He said,
'I went to Blackwater. And I said, 'What
are you doing now? He said, 'I'm head of
security for him.
Wow.
>> And I said, 'Are you getting threats? I
said to the star, "Are you getting
threats?" And he said, "Yeah, I've taken
a position on this Iran thing, and the
threats I'm getting would make your hair
stand up." Well, you've got to take you
have to take everything like that very
seriously because you don't know who's a
nut or who's venting [clears throat] or
who really means business.
There. I had a stalker one time, Josh.
This is right after I went public in
2007.
>> I gave a I gave a speech at Georgetown
University Law School that was carried
on C-SPAN. Who watches C-SPAN? I'll tell
you, one woman in Lincoln, Nebraska was
watching C-SPAN, and [snorts] she
somehow got it into her head that I
proposed to her in code during my
speech.
And so, she started sending me emails.
sometimes as many as 25 or 30 a day
telling me how much she loved me. She
accepted my proposal. This went on for
months. I never ever answered a single
one of the emails. But then
I'm working for the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee. I was the senior
investigator there. And the intern calls
me one morning and said, "John, your
10:00 is here." And I said, "I don't
have a 10:00."
And I said, "Who is it?" He says, "Let
me get her name." He gets her name. He
tells me her name. And I go, "She's in
the building."
And I said, "Hold her there. I'm calling
the cops." So, I call the Capitol
police. They run over. She bolts. But
then she sends me an email later. Like
this very kind of flaky friendly. She
goes, "Silly, why did you call the cops
on me? You know how much I love you. I
just wanted to tell you I brought a gun
with me so I can kill your wife so we
can be together forever.
So I called the cops again. I said,
"Look, she just emailed me. She's in
room 919 of the Harrington Hotel. She's
armed and she came here specifically
with the intent to kill my wife." So
they got her. But this is just one lone
nut. You never know what you're going to
have to face.
>> I can't imagine. You know, one that
that's the thing you should call
Netflix. That that's the things that
good series are made out of right there.
But two, two, I you know, I can't
imagine how you have to sift through,
you know, doing what you've been doing
for so long. How do you sift through the
the the the legitimate threats and the
non-legitimate threats and the ones you
think will never happen or the ones like
this where you have a, you know, a crazy
lady from Lincoln, Nebraska coming and
and trying to kill your wife? Well, you
know, that seems like such a challenge.
>> It's a big challenge. And I'll tell you
what, part of the problem is the the
local police will tell you that there's
nothing they can do because it's an
interstate. You know, these calls come
from everywhere. They're routed
everywhere. And half of the time these
people use Google Voice, so you don't
know where they're calling from. It's
untraceable. Um, I'll tell you what
happened to me recently. I gave a
podcast interview in which I said that
Raza Palvi, the crown prince of Iran,
was a clown. That was the word I used. I
said he's a clown. He doesn't want to go
back to Iran. His wife is cheating on
him with her French personal trainer.
The guy's a disgrace, and he would not
survive the walk from the plane to the
terminal were he to go back to Iran.
That's my position.
Some guy called me 72 times in three
hours. I kept blocking the calls. He
used six different Google voice numbers,
leaving me the filthiest, most vile
voicemails. Okay, who cares? But then he
said, "I can't wait to see your brains
spread out on the sidewalk in front of
one, two, three mainstream." But he
said, "My address, my home address." So,
I called the FBI and [snorts] I'm
telling them the story from the
beginning and they're like, "Yeah, you
know, this happens to people all day
long, all the time." And then I said,
you know, the threat with my address.
And then he said, "And what about your
son? When was the last time you talked
to your son? You know, the one that
lives at 123 High Street, Cincinnati,
Ohio." And I was like, "Okay, you've
gone too far." So, when I told the FBI
agent that, he was like, "Oh, that's a
crime." Okay. So, they picked it up.
They found the guy. It took him 4 days
and he was just some nut in New York who
saw the interview, took exception with
it, and decided he was going to try to
silence me. I got a death threat a week
ago where this idiot used his actual
name, email, and phone number. He's the
CEO of a medical NGO,
didn't like what I said on the Pierce
Morgan show, and threatened to come down
to Washington and blow my brains out. So
the FBI, I sent it to the FBI and the
guy's like, "Thank you. We're gonna
drive over there. We're going to tell
him cut it out." He said, "But if it
happens again, are you willing to press
charges?" And I said, "Yes, of course I
am."
>> So you got to take That's a long way of
saying you have to take everything
seriously. You have to.
>> You know, I uh I've been I've been doing
news for for a little while and I've
gotten some pretty hateful comments.
Haven't made haven't gotten death
threats yet. Clearly, I haven't made
them, John. I haven't I haven't I just
haven't gotten there yet [laughter]
>> to that level. So, I have not called uh
you know a foreign leader a clown yet,
but I'm sure that that's probably down
the road, not not too long. So, I I got
to I gota I don't want to take too much
of your time, but I you know, there's
this dying question that I have. Uh you
know, we kind of talked a little bit
about it and some of the things that
you've learned. I feel like what is the
one thing if you had to if you had to
narrow it down and maybe we've already
talked about it. What is that one thing
that you learned in all your training
and all your experience in Pakistan and
abroad and here? What is that one thing
that you still do every day? That one
thing that you take with you and it
still creeps into your daily life every
day? Because I I I know I have a couple
and I'm sure you do, too.
>> Oh, yeah. Josh, I took surveillance
detection so seriously that when I
returned from Pakistan after 911, I
became a surveillance and surveillance
detection instructor at the agency. And
then I went on to write a book called
The CIA Insiders Guide to Surveillance
and Surveillance Detection. I've I've
been out of the CIA for 22 years,
and I still
am constantly scanning my mirrors.
constantly.
>> You just never know.
>> But and and but you said it too. You
know, look, the average person is not
getting surveiled by the Pakistani
government. No, those are the same
tactics that because people are getting
surveiled. They're getting surveiled by
possible targets. We all know that
people that criminals that the vast
majority of criminals are are
opportunists and that they're there
because they think that they found an
easy target.
>> It's the carjacker. It's it's the thief
who sees that you put the the purse on
the on the passenger seat and is going
to smash the window and grab the purse.
But I'll add one other thing.
>> I as a hobby I like to write television
pilots. And I've been, knock on wood,
I've been very successful in the last 15
years. I've sold eight of them.
>> Holy crap.
>> The very first one that I sold was
called uh Bomb Squad. It was a
procedural and it was a day in the life
of the New York City Bomb Squad. And the
reason I wrote it is because I had a
friend who was assigned a New York City
bomb squad and he said the most
interesting thing and I'm equating this
with surveillance.
He said fewer
than one out of a hundred
bomb threats call-ins to the police have
to do with terrorism. Maybe one out of a
thousand. But he said almost every bomb
threat, bomb scare or actual bomb is a
jilted spouse or lover, an insurance
scammer,
or a mafia hit.
>> Wow.
>> They have nothing to do with terrorism.
>> Yep.
>> Meaning the victims are just average
normal people going about their normal
daily business.
So everybody needs to be aware of his or
her surroundings. Everybody has to be
personally responsible for his or her
own safety and security.
>> Man, I I I couldn't have said it better.
You know, I say so many times, you are
your own first responder, and you have
to treat it like that because
unfortunately, look, I a career cop for
more than two decades, but I'm here to
tell you, we're there to clean up the
mess most of the time.
>> Amen. you know, with an average response
time of about five to seven minutes as
as a national average, it's been over
for for about six minutes at that point.
>> Yeah. You you've been laying in the
street for six minutes. Yes. So, so man
I that personal accountability and
responsibility John is is you just you
really hit the nail on the head and is
so critically important and you know
from someone with this kind of
experience here overseas un trained by
some of the best people in the absolute
world, the best in the world,
>> but it still boils down to that. It
still boils down to basic situational
awareness on an elevated level. Just the
the the production of fundamentals on
demand all the time. But that's what it
comes down to. Man, what a what a great
way to illustrate that.
>> Just force yourself to practice,
practice, practice
>> and and then it becomes habit, right?
You you you're deliberate. You're you're
committed to it. You're deliberate about
it for so long and then all of a sudden
you just do it and it's just part of the
day and it's just part of your habit.
And I think it's it's important to note
it's not about being paranoid. It's not
about being thinking that everyone's out
to get you. It's just understanding and
taking, like you said, personal
accountability and responsibility for
your personal safety and that of your
families. And I think that's so
incredibly important.
>> Oh yeah. May I add one other thing,
Josh?
>> One of the little
tricks or tools that they taught us at
the CIA, and it it's so logical, and I
would never have thought of it, but they
taught us not to ever play the radio
while we were driving.
>> Um, that way you're not distracted. So,
don't play the radio. Instead, speak out
loud to yourself about what you're
seeing. White male, blue jeans, mid-50s,
walking a dog, black female, yellow
sweater, you know, whatever. So that if
you see the white male, black t-shirt
walking a dog again five miles from now,
you know that you've got a potential
problem.
>> What an interesting, you know, almost
like a Kim's game. So yeah,
>> uh I spent a long time as a as a sniper
with SWAT and we'd play Kim's games all
the time, which is just like that, you
know, remembering those observations and
making those observations in a way like
you said, using pneumonics, using just
speaking out loud so that you know you
see it again, you know it, and it it
makes a mark in your mind. Man, how how
great of a tip uh just just for the
average person to be able to do to train
their that situational awareness. How
cool. How cool. John, thank you so much,
man. We I could go on and talk for
hours, but uh [laughter] but this has
been so enlightening and and such an
incredible look into somebody that has
all that experience and how they live
their day-to-day life. Uh I I'd love to
How can people find out more, learn more
about you and about what you're you're
advocating for?
>> And and more of your stories.
>> Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. I'm
pretty much out there all over the
place, but I'll tell you, I'm launching
a new podcast on YouTube starting July
1st. It's at real John Kuriyaku. It's
going to be called John Kuryaku's
Briefing Room. So, you can go and I
would really genuinely appreciate it if
people would subscribe. Uh, so it's
coming in four weeks. Real John Kuryaku.
And I've got another podcast that's
proven to be crazy popular. We're we're
number six in the world in the history
uh category. There there are six million
podcasts out there. Um, we're number 238
overall. It's crazy. But it's called
John Kuryaku's Deadrop. And we're just
now going to finish season two. So there
there are a lot of episodes out there,
>> man. Burner Nation, go and check that
out. Go check out Deadrop. It's already
on my list. When I saw you was like,
"Oh, yes. I got to put this on my list."
And then Jer Kuryaku's The Briefing. Is
that correct?
>> Briefing room.
>> Briefing room. Uh coming out here in
just a few weeks. Go subscribe. I It's
going to be incredible. If you haven't
heard, we got to hear a couple stories
today, but if you haven't heard some of
John's stories, they're absolutely
incredible during a time when, you know,
this whole world was just just
absolutely upside down and just just
such incredible stories. John, thank you
so much for joining us today. I hope I
can have you on again later. We can talk
about everything that's going on.
Burning Nation, join us on the next
episode of Burnab Bros.